Timothy Proctor

20 Sylvan Valley Ave, Auckland, Titirangi Mobile: 027 296 2600

Email: <u>Tim.Proctor@Live.com</u> | Website: <u>www.timproctor.co.nz</u>

GitHub: Tim-Proctor / TimProctorAUT (Uni) | DOB: 12 / 08 / 1998

Skills:

Technical Skills:

Languages:

- HTML and CSS
- SQL
- JavaScript with React
- C# & ASP .NET

Frameworks and Methodologies:

- Xamarin
- Flutter
- Agile Methodologies (SCRUM and KANBAN)

Tools:

- VS Code and VS Studio (2013, 2016, 2017)
- GIT Bash and GitHub
- •
- Postman API Queries
- Windows and Linux CLI
- Microsoft Office

Other Skills and Knowledge:

- Some Academic Cisco Networking Experience
- Understanding of ITIL and COBIT
- Experience with Mobile App Development
- Academic experience with Database Design and Development
- Work based Experience with EDI standards X12 and Edifact for product-based EDI Transactions.

Communication and Customer Support Skills:

I am confident in taking and providing criticism; I am open to changes that may need to be made and I'm not frightened to take the lead in a situation if needed. I have experience working in a professional relationship with a client as well as taking calls and assisting customers in a professional manner.

Planning and Organisation Skills:

I have always made it a priority to keep myself on top of all due dates for my workload. For example, in my third year of university, while working on a full year mobile development project, I also had course work for Python based Text Recognition script that I needed to write as well as a React and Nodejs based Web app. These all required me to learn new syntaxes and libraries which meant that I needed to be extremely organised in how much time I would give to each project. I planned out a workflow, that gave me time to learn the new syntax, library, and language.

Problem Solving:

I enjoy finding solutions to problems; I enjoy the challenge of being put in a situation where I need to adapt and overcome errors or issues and find possible work arounds. I find that this is a regular occurrence when it comes to programming which has led me to learn more programming languages and syntaxes.

SCRUM and Agile Methodology Knowledge:

I have been trained and have experience in using Agile Methodologies like SCRUM and KANBAN. During University a large area of education was development processes and frameworks that are used in the industry. We were introduced to Agile methodologies and were expected to complete multiple internal projects following these frameworks. Also, for the final project when we had to complete a project for a real-world client, SCRUM was our framework of choice. During that project for the first half I was SCRUM Master which was the role in which someone will ensure processes of the framework are being followed.

Education:

Auckland University of Technology (AUT):

Jan 2017 to Dec 2019

Qualifications:

- Bachelor Computer and Information Science, Majoring in Software Development, 2019
- Passing with a B+ Average.

Green Bay High School:

Jan 2012 to Dec 2016

Qualifications:

- NCEA Level 1 with Excellence, 2014
- NCEA Level 2, 2015
- NCEA Level 3 with Excellence, 2016
- NCEA Level 3, Digital Technologies Programming with Merit, 2016

Awards:

- Top in Subject Digital Technologies (Programming) Level 2, 2015
- Top in Subject Digital Technologies (Programming) Level 3, 2016
- The Trusts Community Foundation Award, 2016

Work Experience:

Cin7

Nov 2020 to Present

EDI/3PL Technical Support Technician (Tier 1 & 2):

Is worked as a support team member for the first 6 months, Where we help customers who had integrated connections with 3rd Party Logistics warehouses (3PL) and Transacted with Big Box Retailers through EDI (Electronic Data Interchange) for order requests. This role included the following responsibilities.

- Troubleshooting Customers issues and Responding in a Professional and Cohesive manner over the phone or via Email.
- Handling customer Escalations and prioritising a large backlog of support tickets.
- Simplifying Complex Technical Systems into something Nontechnical Staff and customers can understand as well as Helping walk customers throw standardized workflows.
- Creating Bugs and Development Task Requests for our Developers.
- Debugging System Source Code to locate Bugs and Errors on a Local Development Environment.
- Testing Potential Releases and Fixes for Bugs.
- Supporting a range of different systems using different formats. (EDI, API, FTP, SFTP).

Integrations Analyst:

As an Integrations Analyst I am now building new connections between EDI Retailers and our Customer base, and this role include must of the same details from above plus the following differences.

- Building new EDI & 3PL integrations with our customers and 3rd party teams.
- Reviewing technical Integration Guide and Documentations.
- Running Compliance Tests for new integrations
- Working with EDI standards X12 and Edifact for Product based EDI Transactions.

AUT Work Experience (Lifespan Trust)

Jan 2019 to Nov 2019

Team Developer / SCRUM Leader:

During the last year of university we were expected to complete a paper called Research and Development where you were given a team, a real world client, and were expected to independently undertake and manage a project for a client with one mentor selected from the AUT Staff to support our group.

Our project was to work with a client Lifespan Trust where we needed to develop an android application. For the project we developed the app using Google's multiplatform framework 'Flutter' this was so that the client could easily port the application over to IOS in the future. We used SCRUM an Agile Methodology to facilitate the project.

All members were expected to develop portions of the app, and the SCRUM Leader role meant that I would operate Team Daily Standups and Ensure we were completing all expected SCRUM Processes that we had selected.

This application was completed at the end of the year, and as a team we produced a website that the client could use to download the app while they waited to organise setting up the app for the google play store. This app was release under the name 'Nap Optimizer' and is currently available on the google play store.

- Mobile Development with Flutter Framework
- Dart Programming
- Following and Managing Agile Processes.
- Communicate with a Client
- Operate professional Meetings.
- Creating Supporting Document for a project i.e. Project Briefs/ Project Proposal

NZ Uniforms

Sales Assistant, December 2017 - October 2018.

Dec 2017 to April 2019

I started working at NZ Uniforms at the New Lynn Branch full time during University summer break. I worked from Monday to Saturday, initially as a Stock Runner but then I quickly moved into a floor Sales Assistant roll and finally to a Point of Sales Assistant operating the cash register. I later managed the store on Saturdays by myself and assisted the Store Manager during the week on days I was free. My roles tasks included:

- Stocking Shelves
- Heavy Lifting
- Processing Web Orders
- Assisting Customers
- Taking Customer Phone Calls
- Processing Sales
- EFPOS and Cash Handling.
- Daily Banking and Accounts
- Opening and Closing the Store
- Independently managing and operating a store.
- Using POS and CRM Software ACT and Accredo.

Assistant Manager, October 2018 - April 2019

- o Assisting in Training New Team Members.
- Ability to manage a team of 2-3 staff members.
- o Helping with defusing situations involving difficult customers.
- Relaying Expected Daily Sales goals to team members

CMI Springs

Dispatch Temp Worker.

Dec 2016 to Jan 2017

- Packing products into Boxes and bags while counting to make sure there is a correct amount in each.
- o Re-stocking Shelves and Collecting Stock to Pack from said shelves.
- o Heavy Lifting.
- Working with different equipment like Hydraulic Presses and CNC machine.
- Using palette trolley.

Hobbies and Interests:

Guitar:

I have been learning to play guitar since I was seven years old. I current focus on playing on Classical Guitar and am learning to sight-read sheet music.

Camping:

I enjoy camping with friends and family or just myself. I find that taking some time to enjoy the countryside to be relaxing and great in helping clear my head.

Dungeons and Dragon:

I meet up with a group of friends to play, this cooperative roleplaying game where we must solve problems and adapt to changes while working as a team.

References:

(More reference on request)

Rajeev Kalbag, Former NZ Uniforms Manager

(Number Available on Request)

Mick Rust, Family Friend

(Number Available on Request)